# **Zaw Myo Latt**

# **Back-end Developer**

Address – Blk 93, #04-3037, Paya Lebar Road, Singapore 370093.

Mobile – +6587847812, Email – <u>zawmyolatt.ucsy@gmail.com</u>

Linkedin – https://www.linkedin.com/in/zaw-myo-latt-57449979

Skype – zawmyolatt1122

### **Summary**

My name is Zaw Myo.Graduated from the University of Computer Studies, Yangon (UCSY) in Myanmar and got a Bachelor of Science in Computer Information and Technology (B.C.Sc). Experiences and knowledge obtained through university life and work experiences. After graduating from university, I have an interest in the web application area. That's why I worked as a web developer for over 1 year. Then, I was promoted as a Team Leader at the same company iKloudit Myanmar Office (iKloudit is a Singapore Company), locally called Ever Crystal One-stop IT Solution. There, we have to write the web app projects, which were sold in our Singapore Head Office such as HR System, POS System, CMS and other E-commerce System etc,.

Then after 3 years, I joined <u>GMBF Group of Companies</u> (which was founded myanmar) as an IT Manager.In GMBF, i took the responsibility of project management, task management, mobile apps and web apps development like Bus Ticket Booking system, Coupon based marketing development system etc. After 2 years later, I moved to Singapore at Feb 2019 and joined as **Back-End Developer** in <u>Carpal Fleet</u>. And at the sametime, I founded a freelance software company in Myanmar with a friend at 2017, called <u>Pro-X Software Solution</u>. That also developing many software development services in Myanmar for many platforms.

## **Educational Background**

### **Bachelor's Degree of Computer Science/Information Technology**

Major: Software Engineering

Institute/University: University of Computer Studies, Yangon, Myanmar

Current Specialization: Web Technology – Web Application – Back-end Services

Graduated Date: May 2013

#### **Honors and Certificates**

2010-2011 - Durosoft Web Studio, Certified in advanced PHP (Now Fairway web)

2011-2012 - Certified in Practical Network Course

- Certified the Excellence in IT Business Plan Contest 2013(ICCNA)

- Winner team of Contest on Technopreneurship 2014

(Conducted by Myanmar-Korea IT Center)

#### **Personal Particulars & Preferences**

Date of Birth: 12 Jan 1993

Nationality: **Myanmar** 

#### **Skills Summary**

- **Web Technologies & Frameworks**: Angular, Vue, Ionic, HTML, CSS, PHP, Python, Laravel, Yii, Code Igniter, Django, Aws Services, chalice Serverless, Lambda, SNS, SQS etc.
- **Scripts/UI**: JavaScript, Typescript, JQuery, AJAX, BootStrap, Backbonejs
- Database and ORM: MySQL, SQL, Dynamodb, Elasticsearch, sqlite
- **Application/Web Server**: Apache, Nginx, Expressjs, Nodejs
- Versioning and other tools: Git, Bitbucket, Jira
- **Deployment Tools**: Docker, Vagrant, CI/CD, Laravel Forge

## **Experiences**

### iKloudit (Web Developer)



Oct 2013 - 2014

- Developed web applications by using PHP framework like code igniter/ laravel, etc
- Most of the applications which I developed, there are POS System, Invoicing System, HR System and LMS System etc.



#### **Ever Crystal** (Team Lead)

Oct 2015 - 2018

- Developed web api services and also did integration with some kind of api interface like rest, soap.
- Also develop hybrid mobile application by using ionic1 and angular1,cordova etc
- Most of the applications which I developed, there are Reward System, HR System and Ecommerce System etc.

## **GMBF Group of Companies** (IT Manager)



Nov 2018 - Dec 2019

- Did cloud server management, CI/CD and git branching strategy
- Also develop hybrid mobile application by using ionic 3/4 and angular 6/7, cordova etc
- Most of the applications which we developed are Reward System, HR System, Ecommerce System, Bus Ticketing System and other travel & tour related systems.

## **Carpal Fleet** (Back-End Developer)



#### Jan 2019 - Present

- Developing web application fleet api by using mainly laravel (PHP) for solving vehicle routing and allocating the order driver efficient and effectively
- For the storage we use mainly mysql and also use some AWS services like s3, dynamodb and elasticsearch for indexing data
- used pub/sub messaging architecture for validating, dispatch & allocate orders by using AWS Lambda and SNS
- Writing unit tests and setup pipeline for CI/CD using docker

• Developing some user analytic script and micro services are using python and Chalice(python framework)

### **Languages**

Language	Spoken	Written
Burmese	Native	Native
English	Intermediate	Advance
Tamil	Beginner	-

### **Communication Skill**

I worked together with the Singapore Marketing Team to communicate on Skype, since 2014 when i worked at ikloudit. And also in previous companies, I worked together with some foreign scrum master, product managing guys as remote. So, I am able to communicate effectively with a wide range of people, by showing interest and carefully listening to their needs. Strong presentation and demonstrating skills; Confident, articulate and professional speaking abilities.

Additional Basic Knowledge and Skills

- Django
- GoLang
- Kotlin
- flutter
- React Native